Finding Aid for Walker Lee Cisler Papers 1899-1994
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Walker Lee Cisler Papers
1899-1994
1943-1987
Cisler, Walker Lee, 1897-
Detroit Edison executive, advocate of the need to develop peaceful uses for nuclear power. The papers of Walker L. Cisler are divided into nine series: Atomic Power Development Associates (APDA), Detroit Edison, War Service, Personal File, Speeches, Overseas Advisory Associates (OAAI), Other Affiliations, Visual Materials, and Sound Recordings.
9573 Aa 2
33 linear feet
1 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library University of Michigan
The papers (donor no. 8314 ) were donated by the estate of Walker L. Cisler in 1994.
The collection is open for research.
Walker Lee Cisler was born in Marietta, Ohio in 1897, the son of a country doctor. At the age of four his parents divorced, and Cisler was subsequently raised by his mother in Wallingford, Pennsylvania. In 1917, following his graduation from Westchester High school in 1913, Cisler enrolled in Cornell University. Interrupting his schooling, Cisler saw brief service in the infantry during the First World War. He returned to Cornell in 1919 where he majored in mechanical engineering. He graduated in 1922.
After college, Cisler accepted a cadet position with the Public Service Electric and Gas Company of New Jersey. Cadets were groomed for upper level administrative positions within the company. During this two year appointment, on-the-job training was augmented by participation in company study groups and evening courses in business and economics at New York University. Over the next two decades, Cisler rose through the ranks and eventually became Assistant General Manager of Power Plants.
In 1941 Cisler was appointed to the Office of Production Management (OPM), a division of the War Production Board (WPB). The OPM was composed of three industry consultants working in conjunction with federal planners to coordinate production for civilian and military consumption. As a member of the Power Division, Walker Cisler was responsible for balancing allied demands for electricity against domestic power requirements.
While engaged in this war service, Cisler accepted a position as Chief Engineer of Power Plants with the Detroit Edison Company. Effective October 1, 1943, this appointment was not actualized immediately as Cisler was first commissioned as a Lieutenant Colonel in the United States Army and sent to the Mediterranean theatre to survey electrical facilities. This three-month term of service was repeatedly extended and a promotion to full Colonel followed. In 1944, on the recommendation of the Secretary of the Army, Walker Cisler was appointed to General Eisenhower's staff as Chief of the Public Utilities Section, Supreme Headquarters, Allied Expeditionary Forces (SHAEF). In this position, he assumed primary responsibility for the restoration of electrical services in recently liberated areas.
With the cessation of hostilities in Europe, Cisler served in Berlin as Chief of the Public Utilities Section in the Office of Military Government of Germany. Even with the termination of his active duty status in late 1945, Cisler continued his involvement in European reconstruction as principal advisor to the State Department on electrical power issues. He also worked as chief consultant on electrical power to the Economic Cooperation Administration (ECA) and successor organizations, the Mutual Security Agency (MSA), the Foreign Operations Administration (FOA), and the International Cooperation Administration (ICA). Cisler was officially discharged from military service in 1952.
Upon his return from Europe in 1945, Cisler assumed the duties of Chief Engineer of Power Plants with the Detroit Edison Company. By 1947 he had also been appointed Vice President of Employee Relations. In 1948, his expanded duties were consolidated under the title executive vice president. In 1951, he was appointed to the Board of Directors and subsequently promoted to President and General Manager. Upon the retirement of Prentiss M. Brown in 1954, Walker Cisler was confirmed as Chief Executive Officer of Detroit Edison. He served in this capacity until 1971 at which time he was succeeded by William G. Meese. In 1964 Walker Cisler was elected Chairman of the Board of Directors, a post he held until 1975.
While at Detroit Edison, Walker Cisler focused a great deal of attention on the development of atomic power as a commercial resource. To this end he served as Executive Secretary to the Industrial Advisory Board of the Atomic Energy Commission (AEC) beginning in 1947. Under his direction, the board issued a report to the AEC in 1951 requesting permission to begin industrial development of a fast neutron breeder reactor. This report led directly to a feasibility study conducted by the newly formed Nuclear Power Development Department of the AEC. By 1953, twenty-six power utilities and large corporations nationwide had expressed interest in collaborating on the project. And in 1954, Congress amended the Atomic Energy Act and thus empowered the AEC to license the distribution of fuel for commercial nuclear development and to exercise oversight of construction and safety standards.
Having cleared all legal obstacles to the construction of a commercially managed nuclear reactor, a consortium of electric power systems, engineering, and manufacturing firms established in 1954 the Atomic Power Development Corporation (APDA). Recognized as a leader in the field, Walker Cisler agreed to serve as President and to work to coordinate collaboration in the research and development of a fast neutron breeder reactor. Power Reactor Development Associates (PRDC), a companion corporation to APDA was established to handle actual construction and operation of the first commercially managed nuclear reactor. With Walker Cisler as President in 1956, PRDC functioned as a legal buffer in limiting the liability of APDA's member organizations. Under Cisler's guidance, APDA and PRDC jointly constituted a vehicle for national participation in the development of the Enrico Fermi Nuclear Power Plant at Lagoona Beach, Monroe County, Michigan. As a member of both APDA and PRDC and through the involvement of its managerial and technical personnel, Detroit Edison participated in the construction and operation of Fermi. Detroit Edison also owned and operated the steam generators and steam turbine facilities needed to convert heat generated by the reactor into electrical power suitable for distribution.
Over the next seventeen years, from 1955 to 1972, Cisler and the Fermi plant were closely associated in the public's mind. Despite the ultimate failure of the plant (the reactor was decommissioned in 1972), Cisler never wavered in his espousal of the need to develop peaceful uses for nuclear power. He also saw the need to involve the international community in this effort. He was among the founders of the World Power Conference (WPC) and its successor organization, the World Energy Conference (WEC). In 1968, Cisler was elected chairman of the International Executive Council of WEC, and in 1974, under his leadership, Detroit hosted the meeting of the full body of the WEC.
Cisler retired from Detroit Edison in 1975, but remained active in the international energy scene primarily through his work with Overseas Advisory Associates Inc. (OAAI), which he had founded in 1972 to utilize the expertise of retired energy executives for overseas consulting. OAAI functioned globally, but focused on activity in the Middle and Far East. The most intensive OAAI contracts involved the establishment of a modern energy infrastructure in Saudi Arabia.
In addition, Cisler was active in scientific, civic, political, and business affairs throughout his career. He served as the long-time Chairman of the Thomas Alva Edison Foundation. He also served on the boards of directors of a wide range of organizations devoted to revitalizing Detroit and improving the public welfare. He presided over many programs sponsored by the Economic Club of Detroit and served as a member and interim Chairman of Freuhauf Corporation's Board of Directors.
Walker Cisler remained active in his many endeavors until his death on October 18, 1994 at the age of 97.
The papers of Walker L. Cisler are divided into nine series: Atomic Power Development Associates (APDA), Detroit Edison, War Service, Personal File, Speeches, Overseas Advisory Associates (OAAI), Other Affiliations, Visual Materials, and Sound Recordings.
Subjects:
Cisler, Walker L. (Walker Lee), 1897-1994; Atomic Power Development Associates, inc.; Detroit Edison Company.; Economic Club of Detroit.; Electric power--Michigan.; Enrico Fermi Nuclear Power Plant (Mich.); Fruehauf Corporation.; New Detroit, Inc. (Detroit, Mich.); Nuclear power plants--Michigan.; Overseas Advisory Associates, Inc.; Power Reactor Development Company.; World Power Conference.; World War, 1939-1945.
Subjects - Visual Material:
Cisler, Walker L. (Walker Lee), 1897-1994; Detroit Edison Company.; Enrico Fermi Nuclear Power Plant (Mich.)
Genre/Form:
Photographs.
- Atomic Power Development Associates (APDA), 1950-1977
  The Atomic Power Development Associates (APDA) series (13 linear ft.; 1950-1977), is composed of two sub-series: President's File, and APDA Technology Reports. The APDA President's File contains records of WLC's APDA and Power Reactor Development Associates (PRDC) activities. These files relate principally to the development, construction, administration, and operation of the Enrico Fermi Nuclear Power Plant and auxiliary facilities. The APDA Technology Reports (267 volumes with index) detail the results of research conducted in conjunction with the large fast breeder reactor development program.
  - President's File, 1953-1977
    - Index, Undated (Box 1)
    - APDA Bylaws, 1955-1969 (Box 1)
    - APDA Annual Reports, 1955-1971
      - 1955-1963 (Box 1)
      - 1964-1971 (Box 1)
    - Incoming Correspondence, 1955-1970
      - 1955-1961 (Box 1)
      - 1962-1965 (Box 1)
      - 1966-1970 (Box 1)
    - Incoming Memoranda, 1960-1971 (Box 1)
    - Outgoing Correspondence, 1957-1971 (Box 1)
    - Atomic Energy Commission, 1960-1970
      - General, 1960-1969 (Box 1)
      - Notes on Commission Visits, 1961-1970 (Box 1)
    - Dow Chemical/Detroit Edison Memo of Understanding, 1954-1955 (Box 1)
    - Edison Electric Institute (EEI), 1957-1974
      - General, 1957-1971 (Box 1)
      - Fermi Solicitation, 1971-1972
        - 1971 (Box 1)
        - 1972, 2 folders (Box 1)
      - Plutonium Fuel Program, 1965-1970 (Box 1)
      - Liquid Metal Fast Breeder Reactor Program, 1968-1971 (Box 1)
      - Policy Committee on Atomic Power, 1967-1974; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Fermi Incident, 1966-1970 (Box 2)
    - Fermi Incident (History of), 1968 (Box 2)
    - Fermi Forecasts and Oxide Core Program, 1972 (Box 2)
    - Foreign Agreements, 1971-1972 (Box 2)
    - Imports, Fuel Elements, 1968-1969 (Box 2)
    - Joint Committee on Atomic Energy, 1954-1969
      - General, 1954-1969 (Box 2)
      - Price-Anderson, 1965 (Box 2)
      - Private Ownership, 1963-1964 (Box 2)
    - Legal-Legislation, 1958-1971 (Box 2)
    - Mailing Lists, 1970 (Box 2)
    - Master Plan, 1967-1968 (Box 2)
    - Meetings, Internal, 1956-1972
      - 1956-1962 (Box 3)
      - 1963-1969 (Box 3)
      - 1970-1972 (Box 3)
    - Member Company Commitments, 1954-1973 (Box 3)
    - Merger APDA/PRDC, 1971-1972 (Box 3)
    - Organization and Charts, 1954-1971 (Box 3)
    - Odd Letters, 1953-1958 (Box 3)
    - Personnel (Biographies), 1961-1973 (Box 3)
    - Power Reactor Development Co., 1956-1975
      - General, 1956-1975; 2 folders (Box 3)
      - Annual Reports, 1956-1971 (Box 3)
      - Agreements, CRIEPI, BMI Drafts, BN-RWE, 1972 (Box 3)
      - Application for License Construction and Operation, 1956-1972
        - 1956-1962 (Box 3)
        - 1963-1964 (Box 3)
        - 1965-1972 (Box 3)
      - Executive Committee Meetings and Minutes, 1972 (Box 4)
      - Hearings, etc., 1956-1971
        - 1956-1958 (Box 4)
        - 1959-1960, 2 folders (Box 4)
        - 1961-1971 (Box 4)
      - Stason History Outline, 1971 (Box 4)
    - Prospective Members, 1954-1964 (Box 4)
    - Publicity, 1954-1977
      - 1954-1964 (Box 4)
      - 1966-1969 (Box 4)
      - 1970 (Box 4)
      - 1971-1977 (Box 4)
    - Quarry, 1959-1968
      - General, 1959-1963
        - 1959-1963 (Box 4)
        - 1964-1969 (Box 4)
      - Byproduct Material License, 1963-1968 (Box 4)
    - Tax Ruling, 1956-1966 (Box 4)
    - Utilization of Fermi, 1957-1972
      - 1957-1969 (Box 5)
      - February 1970-October 1970 (Box 5)
      - November 1970-January 1971 (Box 5)
      - February 1971-March 1971 (Box 5)
      - April 1971-February 1972 (Box 5)
      - March 1972-December 1972 (Box 5)
    - Van Der Spek, 1965-1971 (Box 5)
  - Shoudy File, 1950-1976
    - Detroit Edison Participation (Fermi), 1955-1958 (Box 5)
    - Expenditures and Commitments for Atomic Energy Development, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Fermi Letters, 1970-1975 (Box 5)
    - Fermi Provisional Operating License, 1963 (Box 5)
    - Fermi Retirement, 1972-1974 (Box 5)
    - Fermi Retirement Report, 1974-1975 (Box 5)
    - Fermi Utilization report, 1970 (Box 5)
    - Inaugural Ceremonies (Fermi), August 8, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Inventory of Files Transferred to Fermi, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Michigan Public Service Commission Hearing, 1954-1963 (Box 5)
    - Reactor Proposal, 1950-1955
      - 1950-1955 (Box 6)
      - 1954-1955 (Box 6)
      - 1955 (Box 6)
    - Response to Adverse Publicity, 1966-1976 (Box 6)
    - Special Visits to Fermi, 1957-1963 (Box 6)
  - Special File, 1955-1973
    - Fermi Chronological File, 1971-1973
      - March 1971-December 1971 (Box 6)
      - January 1972-May 1972 (Box 6)
      - June 1972-October 1972 (Box 6)
      - October 1972-December 1972 (Box 6)
      - 1973 (Box 6)
    - Large Fast-Reactor Design Study, 1963
      - Vol. 1 (Box 6)
      - Vol. 2, 2 folders (Box 6)
    - Power Reactor Development Co., 1955-1971
      - Bylaws, Articles, and Licenses, 1955-1971 (Box 6)
      - Contracts and Financial Information, 1956 (Box 6)
  - APDA Technology Reports, 1955-1973
    - Index, 1973 (Box 7)
    - 1955-1962, 36 volumes (Box 7)
    - 1963-1966, 38 volumes (Box 8)
    - 1966-1968, 41 volumes (Box 9)
    - 1968-1971, 47 volumes (Box 10)
    - 1965-1972, 30 volumes (Box 11)
    - 1964-1969, 55 volumes (Box 12)
    - 1955-1972, 20 volumes (Box 13)
- Detroit Edison File, 1945-1989
  The Detroit Edison series (1 linear ft.; 1945-1989) details Walker Cisler's long involvement with the Detroit Edison Company. This series includes annual reports, board materials originally serving a decision support function, correspondence, and topical files relating to the administration of Detroit Edison. Also included are official publications, newspaper clippings, and magazine articles pertaining to Walker Cisler.
  - Table of Organization, 1972-1975 (Box 14)
  - Annual Reports, 1954-1989
    - 1954-1960 (Box 14)
    - 1961-1965 (Box 14)
    - 1966-1970 (Box 14)
    - 1971-1975 (Box 14)
    - 1977-1978, 1981 (Box 14)
    - 1984-1985, 1988-1989 (Box 14)
  - Board Material, 1952-1975
    - Capital Financing of Electric Utilities, 1974 (Box 14)
    - $200 Million Loan, 1975 (Box 14)
    - Dividend Rate Increase, 1952 (Box 14)
    - Fermi 1, 1970 (Box 14)
    - Expenses, 1972
      - Chairman of the Board, 1972 (Box 14)
      - World Energy Conference, 1972 (Box 14)
    - Midwest Energy Resources Co., 1974 (Box 14)
    - Official Start-ups, 1951-1974 (Box 14)
    - Resignation as Chief Executive Officer, 1971 (Box 14)
    - System Development Plans, 1961 (Box 14)
    - System Capability, Load and Budget, 1967-1975 (Box 14)
  - Correspondence, 1947-1973
    - General, 1947-1958 (Box 14)
    - Board of Directors, 1956-1972 (Box 14)
    - Former Directors, 1950-1973
      - Prentiss Brown, 1950-1973 (Box 14)
      - Frederick Mueller, 1961 (Box 14)
    - Response to Negative Press about W. L. Cisler, 1973 (Box 14)
    - W. L. Cisler's War Service, 1945-1946 (Box 14)
  - Financing Recommendation, 1958 (Box 14)
  - Laser Fusion, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Load Study Committee Forecast, 1971-1980 (Box 14)
  - Ludington Pumped Storage Hydroelectric Generating Plant, 1968-1986
    - General, 1968-1986 (Box 14)
    - Transmission Facilities Agreement, 1969 (Box 14)
    - Operating Agreement, 1969 (Box 14)
    - Ownership Agreement, 1969 (Box 14)
    - Project Transmission Agreement, 1969 (Box 14)
  - Management Response to Financial Crisis, 1974 (Box 14)
  - Michigan Electric Power Capacity and Reliability, 1966-1970 (Box 14)
  - Pending Litigation, 1978 (Box 14)
  - Publications, 1947-1982
    - "Adventures in Space", 1960 (Box 14)
    - "Blueprint for the Sixties and the Next Sixty Years", 1963 (Box 14)
    - "Building Fermi-2" (pamphlet), 1976
      - "Partners in Progress" (50th Anniversary), 1953 (Box 14)
    - Synchroscope, 1948-1982
      - 1948 (Box 14)
      - 1968-1969 (Box 14)
      - 1979-1982 (Box 14)
    - "The Year 2000 Study", 1971 (Box 14)
    - "We Did Not Almost Lose Detroit", 1976 (Box 14)
    - Ads for S.E. Michigan Newspapers, 1949-1963 (Box 14)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1947-1974
      - General, 1951-1974 (Box 14)
      - Fermi and Nuclear Power, 1947-1971 (Box 14)
      - W. L. Cisler's election to the Board of Director's, September 1951 (Box 14)
    - Magazine Articles, 1951-1972 (Box 14)
- War Service File, 1918-1919; 1943-1953
  The War Service series (1 linear ft.; 1918-1919 and 1943-1953) documents Walker Cisler's service record and includes, in addition to official document, war-related correspondence and notebooks. This series includes detailed information on power issues in various European nations during the war. Other files document his affiliation with the War Production Board, the Office of the Military Government of Germany, and the Public Utilities Committee (SHAEF).
  - Service Record, 1918-1953 (Box 15)
  - Honorable Discharge, 1919; 1952; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Correspondence, 1943-1945
    - 1943 (Box 15)
    - January 1944-June 1944 (Box 15)
    - July 1944-December 1944 (Box 15)
    - January 1945-June 1945 (Box 15)
    - July 1945-December 1945 (Box 15)
  - Notebooks, Undated (Box 15)
  - Geographical File, 1936-1945
    - Austria & Bavaria, 1945 (Box 15)
    - Belgium, 1936-1939; 1944-1945 (Box 15)
    - France, 1944-1945
      - General, 1944-1945 (Box 15)
      - Paris Region, 1944 (Box 15)
    - Germany, 1944-1945; 2 folders (Box 15)
    - Italy, Undated (Box 15)
    - Switzer, 1945 (Box 15)
  - War Production Board (WPB), 1941-1945
    - Office of War Utilities, 1941-1945
      - General, 1943 (Box 15)
      - "P46" Interpretations, 1941 (Box 15)
      - Personnel, 1944 (Box 15)
      - History of the Office of War Utilities, Undated (Box 15)
      - History of the Steam Turbine and Condenser Section, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Office of Military Government for Germany, 1945-1948
    - General, 1945-1948 (Box 15)
    - Technical Manual for Utilities, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Production Control Agency, 1945 (Box 15)
  - Public Utilities Committee, 1944-1945
    - Combined Production and Resources Board, 1944-1945 (Box 15)
- Personal File, 1933-1994
  The Personal File series (2 linear ft.; 1933-1994), includes genealogical and biographical information, correspondence, publications, and files detailing his many international commitments and activities.
  - Genealogical, 1956-1979; Undated (Box 16)
  - Biographical, 1946-1972
    - General, 1946-1958 (Box 16)
    - Federal Security Clearance Application, 1949-1962 (Box 16)
    - Memoirs, 1972 (Box 16)
  - Correspondence, 1935-1994
    - Committee on Power Generation, 1935-1937 (Box 16)
    - General, 1943-1994
      - 1943 (Box 16)
      - 1944 (Box 16)
      - January 1945-July 1945 (Box 16)
      - August 1945-December 1945 (Box 16)
      - 1946 (Box 16)
      - 1950-1951, 1955-1956 (Box 16)
      - 1964-1994 (Box 16)
  - Contributions, 1953-1972
    - Charitable, 1966-1972 (Box 16)
    - Political, 1953-1972 (Box 16)
  - Hot Springs (Aircraft Accident), 1971-1972 (Box 16)
  - Management of Missile Ranges, 1959-1961 (Box 16)
  - Northwest Power Situation, 1951 (Box 16)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1943-1973; 1985-1990 (Box 16)
  - Publications, 1944-1990
    - 1944-1955 (Box 16)
    - 1959-1963 (Box 16)
    - 1964-1979, 1990 (Box 16)
  - Travel Notebooks, 1949-1972; 27 volumes (Box 16)
  - Gertrude Cisler, 1950-1970 (Box 16)
  - Calendars, 1950-1970; 4 volumes (Box 16)
  - Geographical File, 1942-1977
    - Belgian Congo, 1957 (Box 16)
    - Brazil, 1959 (Box 16)
    - China, 1954; 1965 (Box 16)
    - Eng, 1947-1949; 1969 (Box 16)
    - Europe, 1944-1956
      - Organization of European Energy Cooperation, 1955-1956 (Box 16)
      - Rosenman Report, 1944-1947 (Box 16)
      - European Trip, 1953-1954 (Box 16)
    - France, 1944-1949 (Box 17)
    - Geneva, 1955; Undated (Box 17)
    - Germany, 1942-1952
      - Correspondence, 1946-1952 (Box 17)
      - Decartelization, 1949 (Box 17)
      - Circuit Breakers, 1946-1950 (Box 17)
      - Load Curves, 1942-1945 (Box 17)
      - Technical Industrial Intelligence Committee (TIIC), 1945-1947 (Box 17)
    - India, 1962-1970 (Box 17)
    - Italy, 1953 (Box 17)
    - Japan, 1947-1970 (Box 17)
    - Korea, 1949-1970 (Box 17)
    - Lower Mekong, 1964-1975 (Box 17)
    - Madagascar, 1961 (Box 17)
    - Mexico, 1947-1951 (Box 17)
    - Nigeria, 1951-1952; 1967 (Box 17)
    - Okinawa, 1964-1965 (Box 17)
    - Pakistan, 1961 (Box 17)
    - Russia, 1955-1977
      - General, 1955; 1977; Undated (Box 17)
      - 1958 U.S. Visit, 1958-1959, 2 folders (Box 17)
      - Russians in U.S., 1959 (Box 17)
      - U.S.A. Delegation to U.S.S.R., 1962-1964 (Box 17)
      - U.S.S.R. Delegation to U.S.A., 1963 (Box 17)
    - Taiwan, 1962-1973 (Box 17)
    - Tunisia, 1961 (Box 17)
    - Vietnam, 1970-1973
      - North, 1970 (Box 17)
      - Republic of, 1970-1973 (Box 17)
    - Yugoslavia, 1956 (Box 17)
- Speeches, 1933-1987
  The Speeches series (8 linear ft.; 1933-1987) includes copies of both published and unpublished speeches.
  - Unpublished, 1933-1981
    - 1933-1953 (Box 18)
    - 1955-1958 (Box 19)
    - 1959-1964 (Box 20)
    - 1964-1966 (Box 21)
    - 1966-1971 (Box 22)
    - 1971-1978 (Box 23)
    - 1978-1981 (Box 24)
  - Published, 1943-1987
    - 1943-1956 (Box 24)
    - 1957-1987 (Box 25)
- Overseas Advisory Associates (OAAI), 1974-1993
  The Overseas Advisory Associates (OAAI) series (4 linear ft.; 1974-1993), is composed primarily of geographically organized telexes relating to consulting activities of OAAI. A substantial portion of the file relates to activities in Saudi Arabia.
  - Corporate Information, 1974 (Box 26)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 26)
  - Telexes, 1979-1989
    - General, 1980-1989; 10 folders (Box 26)
    - Belgium, 1980-1981; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Edison International Foundation, 1980-1986; 7 folders (Box 26)
    - Egypt, 1980-1986
      - 1980-1985, 6 folders (Box 26)
      - Management Project, 1986 (Box 26)
    - India, 1983 (Box 27)
    - Italy, 1980 (Box 27)
    - Jamaica, 1981-1983; 3 folders (Box 27)
    - Japan, 1980-1981; 1986
      - 1980-1981, 2 folders (Box 27)
      - CRIEPI, 1986 (Box 27)
    - Korea, 1980-1986
      - 1980 (Box 27)
      - 1982-1985, 4 folders (Box 27)
      - Nuclear Project, 1986 (Box 27)
    - Saudi Arabia
      - 1979 (Box 27)
      - January 1980-March 1980 (Box 27)
      - April 1980-June 1980 (Box 27)
      - July 1980-September 1980 (Box 27)
      - October 1980-December 1980 (Box 28)
      - January 1981-February 1981 (Box 28)
      - March 1981-April 1981 (Box 28)
      - May 1981-September 1981 (Box 28)
      - October 1981-December 1981 (Box 29)
      - 1982-1986, 5 folders (Box 29)
    - Taiwan, 1980-1985; 6 folders (Box 29)